Finding Aid for Cynthia Earl Kerman research files, 1927-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Cynthia Earl Kerman research files 1927-2011 1927-1983
Kerman, Cynthia Earl.
1.3 linear feet (in 2 boxes).
0424 Aa 2
Biographer of Kenneth E. Boulding. Collected information about life and career of Kenneth E. Boulding; tapes and transcripts of interviews with Kenneth E. Boulding and his family and associates; copies of Boulding articles; and photographs used in the biography.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received in 1999 from Cynthia Earl Kerman (donor no. 8876 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Cynthia Earl Kerman is a historian and biographer. She has written biographies of Jean Toomer and Kenneth E. Boulding. She was a professor of English at Villa Julie College in Stevenson, Maryland.
The collection is comprised of Cynthia Kerman's research file on Kenneth E. Boulding. In addition to collected materials, the files include interviews, correspondence, and audio cassettes of conversations with Kenneth Boulding.
Subjects:
Kerman, Cynthia Earl.; Boulding, Kenneth Ewart, 1910-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Kenneth E. Boulding Research Files
  - Bibliographies (KEB) (Box 1)
  - Biography (proposal and development) (Box 1)
  - Bouldingisms (Box 1)
  - Christmas Letters from Bouldings (Box 1)
  - Conflict resolution: history, letters, interviews, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Conversations (various interviews with the Bouldings) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (between CEK and KEB) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (between CEK and KEB regarding book), 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (between CEK and KEB's friends) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Kenworthy chapter) (Box 1)
  - Courtship and first years of marriage (interviews, Elise by CEK) (Box 1)
  - Elise Boulding (peace advocate) (Box 1)
  - Elise Boulding (Writings) (Box 1)
  - Elise Boulding: personal notes and correspondence (Box 1)
  - England: CEK correspondence with KEB's friends (Box 1)
  - England: CEK interviews with KEB's friends (Box 1)
  - Evaluations of KEB and his work (Box 1)
  - Family relations (interviews, CEK with children) (Box 1)
  - Genealogy, KEB: copies of birth, marriage and death certificates, Jane Austen material (Box 1)
  - General Systems (Box 1)
  - Ideas related to KEB (Box 1)
  - Interviews, KEB mature life, with KEB, Elise, and children, 1967-1969, copies of several KEB letters to publishers, etc. (Box 1)
  - Interviews with colleagues, Ann Arbor, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Interviews CEK with KEB, 1980 and 1983 (Box 1)
  - Leary checklist & development charts (Box 1)
  - Notes on wirtings, KEB, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Pictures and notes on pictures (Box 1)
  - Poetry, KEB, chronological 1927-1969 (Box 1)
  - Public pronouncements, 1953-1973 (Box 1)
  - Publicity, 1956-1969 (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Beyond Economics (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Conflict and Defense (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Creative Tension: the Life and Thought of Kenneth Boulding (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Economic Analysis (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Economics of Peace (Box 1)
  - Reviews of The Image (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Impact of the Social Sciences (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Meaning of the Twentieth Century (Box 1)
  - Reviews of The Organizational Revolution (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Principles of Economic Policy (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Reconstruction of Economics (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Skills of the Economists (Box 1)
  - Schellenberg James A. (writer) (Box 1)
  - Spiritual autobiography at Ann Arbor Friends Meeting, July 1967 (Box 1)
  - Study of Values and TAT test (Box 1)
  - Stuttering history (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Press, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - Writings, Elise,1974-2011 (Box 1)
  - Writings, KEB, 1936-1956 (Box 1)
  - Writings, KEB, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
  - Writings, KEB, 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - Writings, KEB, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Writings, KEB, 1966-1969 (Box 2)
  - Writings, KEB, 1972-1983 (Box 2)
  - Audio tapes of conversations with KEB, 1983, 4 cassettes (Box 2)